hello my name's Liz I'm going to give
you an ielt practice speaking test first
I will give you
instructions then I will give you your
speaking test after the test I will give
you a link so that you can get model
answers for all the questions in this
test if you have read the instructions
before on my website you can click here
to start your test in immediately for
this test you will need a pen a piece of
paper a recording device for example
your telephone so that you can record
your answers when you speak and also a
timer so that you can control the time
in the test there are three parts to
this test part one is the
interview part two is a talk and part
three is a chance for you to answer
questions about a world issue or
abstract questions the moment I begin to
ask the first question you must start
your recording device and also your
timer this way you will know the length
of the
test the test should take no more than
11 to 14 minutes for all parts now let
me give you some instructions so that
you know how to work this test after the
the first question pause the video and
answer the question when you finished
answering start the video again and
listen to the next
question pause after you listen and
answer the question continue pausing and
answering the questions until you finish
part one there are 12 questions in part
one the same as your real ielt speaking
test part one can never be more than
five minutes after part one you will
have part two that's the
talk I will give you the topic the Q
card the topic card will appear on the
screen I will explain that you will have
one minute to prepare you will need your
pen and paper for that the time for
Preparation 1 minute will be timed in
the video so don't worry about that I
will will tell you when to start
speaking your talk must last for more
than 1 minute but less than 2
minutes at the end of one minute a
button will appear so if you finish your
talk early you can jump to part three
but it is important to try and keep
talking for 2 minutes at the end of 2
minutes I will stop you if you're still
talking to move on to part three after
part two the there will be part three I
will ask between five to six questions
for part
three just like in part one you need to
listen to the question in the video
press pause and give your
answer when you finished your answer
press the video to play again and listen
to the next question you need to
continue pausing and answering the
questions until the end of part three
part three lasts more than 4 minutes but
less than five
minutes so again if you are taking less
than four minutes you're not giving long
enough answers part three only has five
to six questions so that means you need
to give long answers give lots of detail
and lots of examples and at the end of
the test I will give you a link so that
you can get all the model answers for
the test let's start your ielt practice
speaking test I'd like to talk about
your home do you live in a house or a
flat which is your favorite
room can you describe
it if you could improve one thing about
your house what would it
be let's move on I I'd like to talk
about
films do you enjoy watching
films what kind of films do you like
most did you watch much TV as a
child are foreign language films popular
in your
country let's talk about greeting
people how would you greet someone who
was visiting your house
would you greet an old friend and a
stranger in the same
way how do you meet new
people do you think first impressions
are
important I'd like to move on now I'm
going to give you a topic to talk about
you will need your pen and paper for
this you will have one minute to prepare
and I would like you to speak for 2
minutes I would like you to describe a
holiday you recently had please start
making notes now I will let you know
when it's time to begin
speaking e
could you start speaking now
please
e
e e
thank you I'd like to talk more about
holidays and
traveling if you had the chance to
travel anywhere where would you
go why do you think some people like
traveling
alone do you think travel has changed
much in the last few
decades how does travel change
people do you think there are any
disadvantages to Modern
travel that's the end of your ielt
practice speaking
test now let me give you a link so that
you can get model answers for all the
questions in this test